Almas Baimagambetov

STATEMENT

I am an active researcher in the field of automated diagram generation. I teach a range of Computer Science modules to 1st, 2nd and 3rd year university students. I am the author and maintainer of FXGL, a game engine used by multiple academic institutions to teach game development. I contribute to a number of open-source projects on GitHub. I run an educational YouTube channel covering game and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct. 2017 - Present	Part-time Lecturer & Module Leader in Game Development $University\ of\ Brighton,\ UK$
Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017	Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Programming and Game Design & Development University of Brighton, UK
June 2014 - Oct. 2016	English-Russian Interpreter (Zero-Hour Contract) $LLP\ AktubNIGRI,\ Kazakhstan$
Jan 2013 - Oct. 2016	In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan
Oct. 2012 - Feb. 2015	Guest Speaker and Mentor for IT students (Volunteer) Bellerbys College, UK

EDUCATION

July 2015 - Oct. 2018	PhD in Computer Science, University of Brighton, UK
(Expected)	Thesis: Automated visualization of grouped networks
	using Euler diagrams and graphs
	keywords: set theory, graph theory, topology,
	computational geometry & graphics
Oct.2012 - July 2015	BSc Computer Science (Games), University of Brighton, UK
	Final year project:
	Analysis of software development issues in large scale games
	Project grade: 87% (A+), Degree: 1st Class Honours
Sept. 2011 - June 2012	Foundation Degree in IT, Bellerbys College, UK
	Grade: 94% (A+)

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE (GAMES) GRADES

FINAL YEAR MODULE	Mark/Grade	CREDITS
Mobile Application Development	82% A+	20
Programming Languages, Concurrency	76% A	20
Applied Intelligent Systems	80% A+	10
Emerging Games Technologies	80% A+	20
Computer Graphics Algorithms	91% A+	10
Final Year Project	87% A+	40

Weighted average mark across final year modules: 83%

AWARDS

Sept. 2015	International Research Scholarship (50% fee reduction) University of Brighton
July 2015	Best Final Year Development Project (£250) The FDM Group Prize
Nov. 2014	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000) University of Brighton
Nov. 2013	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000) University of Brighton
June 2012	Top #1 Foundation Student, Bellerbys College
May 2012	Best IT Student, Bellerbys College

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced: Java, JavaFX, Kotlin,

game engine development (ECS, AI, UI, IO, serialization,

physics, event systems, networking, scripting), API design, TDD, FDD, DDD, CI, deployment, software development principles and practices,

algorithms and data structures

Intermediate: C++, JS, SDL2, OpenGL, Git, Win/Mac/Linux, Agile, LATEX Beginner: Unity, SQL, HTML, CSS, Haskell, Python, Node.js, Spring

Interests and Activities

game development, software development, computer science data visualization, automated graphical layout generation education, technology, open-source, chess

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent / Professional

Kazakh: Native Russian: Native

RESEARCH TALKS

June 2018	Generating Effective Euler Diagrams (Upcoming, 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams)
May 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation (University of Brighton Internal Conference)
March 2017	Data Visualization Workshop (Presenter at Data Visualization Brighton Meetup)
Feb. 2017	An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation (Visual Modelling Group Talk)
June 2016	Grouped Networks and Associated Challenges (University of Brighton Internal Conference)

PUBLICATIONS

May 2016

1. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Howse, J., Stapleton, G. and Delaney, A. (2018) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Accepted for long paper).

Euler Diagram Generation Techniques

(Visual Modelling Group Talk)

2. **Baimagambetov**, **A.** (2018) Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Accepted for Graduate Symposium report).